A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, officers' diaries, RG 12, F-L FA392
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Hayes, Guy Scull, 2.66 Cubic Feet 7 letter document boxes
  - 1973 (Box 215)
  - 1974 (Box 215)
  - 1975 (Box 215)
  - 1976 (Box 216)
  - 1977 (Box 216)
- Heiser, Victor G., 0.76 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes
  East Asia
  - Notes on the 1915 Trip
    Includes: Borneo, Java, Straits Settlements, Federated Malay States, Siam, Sumatra, Burma, India, Ceylon, Egypt, Paris and London.
    File Plan
    This item was originally in Rockefeller Foundation records, International Health Board/Division records, RG 5, Series 2 Special Reports.
  - Notes on the 1916 Trip, Vol I.
    Includes: Honolulu, Fiji Islands, Samoa, Tonga, New Zealand, Australia, Papua, Celebes, Java, Straits Settlements, Federated Malay States, Siam.
  - Notes on the 1916 Trip, Vol II.
    Include: Sumatra, Borneo, Philippines, China, Korea, Japan.
  - 1923 (Box 216)
  - 1925-1926 (Box 216)
  - 1927-1929 (Box 217)
  - 1930-1931 (Box 217)
  - 1932-1934 (Box 217)
- Hildebrand, Peter E., 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  - 1974 October-1975 (Box 218)
  - 1976 (Box 218)
  - 1977 January-May (Box 218)
  - 1977- 1979 (Box 218)
  - Agricultural Reports, 1975-1977 (Box 218)
  - Monthly Report, 1978 March-April (Box 218)
- Hill, Rolla B., 1.52 Cubic Feet 4 letter document boxes
  Spain; Portugal
  - 1946-1947 (Box 219)
  - 1948 (Box 219)
  - 1949 (Box 219)
  - 1950 (Box 219)
  - 1951 (Box 220)
  - 1952 (Box 220)
  - 1953 (Box 220)
  - 1954 (Box 221)
  - 1955 (Box 221)
  - 1956 (Box 222)
- Hirst, Esther Mary, 0.76 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes
  - 1944-1947 (Box 222)
  - 1948-1949 (Box 222)
  - 1950-1951 (Box 222)
  - 1952-1953 (Box 223)
  - 1954-1955 (Box 223)
  - 1956-1957 (Box 223)
- Holland, Robert C., 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  - 1969 (Box 223)
- Howard, Hector H., 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  - 1919, 1923 (Box 224)
- Hughes, Thomas Patrician, 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  Born in 1900.
  - 1939-1944 (Box 224)
- Hunter, Thomas Harrison, 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  - 1962-1963 (Box 224)
- Hydrick, John L., 1.52 Cubic Feet 4 letter document boxes
  - 1938-1939 (Box 224)
  - 1940 (Box 225)
  - 1941-1942 (Box 225)
  - 1943 (Box 225)
  - 1946-1947, 1949 (Box 225)
  - 1950 January-June (Box 225)
  - 1950 July-December (Box 226)
  - 1951 (Box 226)
  - 1952 (Box 226)
  - 1953 January-March (Box 227)
  - 1953 March-September (Box 227)
- Jacocks, William P., 0.76 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes
  Ceylon; India
  - 1938-1939 (Box 227)
  - 1940 (Box 227)
  - 1941-1942 (Box 228)
- Janney, John H., 1.14 Cubic Feet 3 letter document boxes
  John H. Janney was born in Brookville, Maryland on July 24, 1893. He was the child of Quaker farmers. When he matured Janney attended the Earlham College, a Quaker college in Richmond, Indiana. He graduated in 1913 with a B.S degree and was determined to go to medical school. Ultimately Janney decided to attend Johns Hopkins Medical School. After he graduated in 1917 he completed a six-month internship and then promptly joined the Army Medical Corp. In the Army Jenny served in London where he treated British Soldiers who had been injured in World War I. He later served in France working on a field Ambulance and as Battalion Medical Officer. During the conflict he was injured by a gas attack and had to spend a great deal of time recuperating. He returned to duty to serve in a convalescent ward for American Officers, where he served until the end of the war.
  Following the end of the war Janney stayed in England, where he attended a three month medical refresher course at the University of Edinburgh. Either while attending the course or as result of his hospital stay after the gas attack he meet a nurse named Brenda Hopkins, who he ended up marrying. The couple would end up having two children. When Janney was reading the Journal of the American Medical Association one day he noticed an ad for the Association for the Adoption of the Metric System that reproduced a letter from General Gorgas which had a Rockefeller Foundation letterhead. Seeking a job, Janney wrote to the address listed in the ad and was appointed the Foundation's International Health Board (IHB). Initially he was assigned to learn about rural health work by serving as a County Health Officer in Beaufort County, North Carolina. In 1921 the IHB member who was slated to do public heath work in Brazil failed his physical examination and so Jenney was sent in his place. He spent six years working in public health in Brazil, initially in Sao Paulo and later in Minas Gerais. Janney also fought to eradicate Hookworm in the country. When he returned to the United State Janney attended Johns Hopkins to receive his Masters in Public Health. He received the degree in 1928. Shortly following the receipt of his degree Janney again worked for the IHB in doing rural health work in the United States. Among several accomplishments he established a model health department in Anne Arduel County, Maryland which worked with the Johns Hopkins School of Public Health.
  Following his time in Maryland the IHB sent Janney to Romania where he did epidemiological work streptococcus among rural populations. He identified several streoticocci bacteria associated with Scarlet Fever. He spent seven months in New York City analyzing this data, the only time Janney would be in New York while working for the Rockefeller Foundation or the IHB. In 1940 Janney was sent by the IHB to Europe to supervise public health, malaria and nursing operations in Portugal and nutrition and nursing in Spain. He was responsible for arrange the importation of $5 million dollars of Red Cross food relief to into Spain in the wake of the Civil War.
  The most high profile part of Janney's career was in Chile where he served as a public health advisor. Initially, he took on the responsibility of assisting in the establishment of a school of public health and worked to create a health unit in the Santiago Suburbs. The public health school that Janney worked to help create began to train its first students for M.P.H degrees in 1944. Janney also assisted in establishing a rural health center in San Felipe. Janney's wife, Brenda Janney worked to train farm workers at the facility because agricultural improvement was seen as a key way of improving nutrition and thereby public health. In 1955 Janney returned to Chile to work with the University of Chile and the Catholic University of Chile to help effectively use the grant money that the Rockefeller Foundation had given them. The Rockefeller Foundation viewed Janney as more reliable then the Chilean's themselves in judging how to spend grant money. The Rockefeller Foundation's Committee of Trustees went as far as to suggest that Janney was "irreplaceable" and that when the history of Chilean Medicine was examined in the future it would be "divided in the pre-Janney, Janney and post-Janney periods."
  For his service Janney received a number of prestigious awards. He was made an honorary member of the Faculty of Medicine at the University of Chile in 1946. In 1951 he received a prestigious commission as a Comendador and later Gran Oficial in the Rioja de O'Higgins Order of Merit from the Chilean government. He left Chile in 1959 and retired to Clarksville, Maryland. Janney suggested that his retirement had three components "Eating and drinking, which is the most dangerous; reminiscing, which is the most boring; and criticizing, which is the most futile." John Janney died on November 19, 1975 in Cantonville, Maryland. He was survived by his wife and children.
  - 1938-1940 (Box 228)
  - 1941-1943 (Box 228)
  - 1949-1950 (Box 228)
  - 1951 (Box 229)
  - 1952-1953 (Box 229)
  - 1954-1955 (Box 229)
  - 1956 (Box 229)
  - 1957 (Box 230)
  - 1958 (Box 230)
  - 1959 (Box 230)
- Jennings, Peter R., 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  - 1975-1977 (Box 230)
- Johnson, Elmer C., 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  - 1966-1970 (Box 231)
- Johnson, Harald N., 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  - 1951-1953 (Box 231)
- Johnson, Lillian A., 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  - 1952-1956 (Box 231)
- Johnston, James E., 0.76 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes
  - 1975-1976 (Box 232)
  - 1977-1978 (Box 232)
  - 1979-1980 (Box 232)
  - 1981-1982 (Box 233)
  - 1983-1984 (Box 233)
- Jones, Lauder W., 1.14 Cubic Feet 3 letter document boxes
  - 1929 (Box 233)
  - 1930 (Box 234)
  - 1931 (Box 234)
  - 1932 (Box 234)
  - 1933 (Box 235)
  - 1934 (Box 235)
- Jordan, Peter, 0.76 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes
  - 1966-1969 (Box 236)
  - 1970-1976 (Box 236)
  - 1977-1978 (Box 237)
- July, Robert W., 1.52 Cubic Feet 4 letter document boxes
  Related Archival Materials note
  See also General Education Board, Series 12.
  - 1955 (Box 237)
  - 1956 (Box 237)
  - 1957 (Box 238)
  - 1958 (Box 238)
  - 1959 (Box 239)
  - 1960 (Box 239)
  - 1961 (Box 240)
  - 1962 (Box 240)
- Kendrick, John F., 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  - 1942, 1946-1948 (Box 241)
- Kerr, John A., 1.05 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes and 1 oversize box
  Philippines; Brazil
  - 1943 (Box 241)
  - 1947 (Box 241)
  - 1951-1952 (Box 241, Box 241A)
  - 1953 (Box 242)
  - 1954-1956 (Box 242)
- King, Woodie, Jr., 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  - 1968-1970 (Box 242)
- Kitchen, Stuart F., 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  - 1946-1949 (Box 242)
- Klein, Howard, 2.28 Cubic Feet 6 letter document boxes
  - 1967-1968 (Box 243)
  - 1969 January-June (Box 243)
  - 1969 July-December (Box 244)
  - 1970 (Box 244)
  - 1971 (Box 244)
  - 1972 (Box 245)
  - 1973 (Box 245)
  - 1974 (Box 245)
  - 1975 (Box 246)
  - 1978 (Box 246)
  - 1979 (Box 246)
  - 1980 (Box 247)
  - 1981 (Box 247)
  - 1982 (Box 247)
  - 1983 (Box 248)
  - 1984 (Box 248)
  - 1986 (Box 248)
- Knipe, Frederick W., 0.76 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes
  Europe, Eastern; India; Italy
  - 1938-1942 (Box 249)
  - 1945-1947 (Box 249)
  - 1948-1950 (Box 249)
  - 1951-1953 (Box 249)
  - 1954-1958 (Box 250)
- Kokernot, Robert H., 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  - 1954-1957 (Box 250)
- Krull, Charles F., 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  - 1960, 1962, 1965-1966 (Box 250)
- Kumm, Herman Henry William, 1.52 Cubic Feet 4 letter document boxes
  - 1938 November- 1939 September (Box 250)
  - 1940, 1942, 1944, 1949 (Box 250)
  - 1959 (Box 251)
  - 1960 January-July (Box 251)
  - 1960 August-December (Box 251)
  - 1961 January-June (Box 252)
  - 1961 July-December (Box 252)
  - 1962 January-June (Box 252)
  - 1962 July-December (Box 253)
  - 1963 (Box 253)
  - 1964 (Box 253)
- Lambert, Robert A., 1.9 Cubic Feet 5 letter document boxes
  - 1928-1929 (Box 254)
  - 1930 (Box 254)
  - 1931 (Box 254)
  - 1932-1933 (Box 255)
  - 1934-1935 (Box 255)
  - 1936-1937 (Box 255)
  - 1938-1939 (Box 256)
  - 1940-1941 (Box 256)
  - 1942 (Box 256)
  - 1943 (Box 257)
  - 1944 (Box 257)
  - 1945 (Box 257)
  - 1946 (Box 258)
  - 1947 (Box 258)
  - 1948 (Box 258)
- Lane, Frederic C., 0.76 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes
  - 1951 (Box 259)
  - 1952 January-April (Box 259)
  - 1952 May-December (Box 259)
  - 1953 January-May (Box 260)
  - 1953 June-December (Box 260)
  - 1954 (Box 260)
- Lathem, Willoughby, 0.76 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes
  - 1968 (Box 260)
  - 1975-1976 (Box 261)
  - 1975-1977 (Box 261)
- Lavine, Steven David, 0.76 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes
  - 1982-1983 Interoffice Memos (Box 261)
  - 1981-1984 Interviews (Box 261)
  - 1984 Interoffice Memos (Box 262)
  - 1985 Interoffice Memos (Box 262)
  - 1986 Interoffice Memos (Box 262)
- Leach, Charles N., 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  - 1935, 1938-1941 (Box 263)
  - 1944-1948 (Box 263)
- Leavell, Hugh R., 0.38 Cubic Feet
  - 1945-1946 (Box 263)
- LeCapelaine, R. R., 0.47 Cubic Feet 1 legal document box
  - 1924-1925 (Box 264)
- Lee, Vernon H., 0.47 Cubic Feet 1 legal document box
  - 1964-1965 (Box 264)
- Lees, Ronald E. M., 0.47 Cubic Feet 1 legal document box
  - 1965-1968 (Box 264)
- Leonard, Irving A., 0.85 Cubic Feet 1 legal document box and 1 letter document box
  - 1937-1940 (Box 264)
  - Field Diary, 1937-1940 (Box 265)
    Field
- Lilly, Percy L., 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  - 1968-1969 (Box 265)
- Lloyd, Norman, 2.28 Cubic Feet 6 letter document boxes
  Norman Lloyd was the Rockefeller Foundation's (RF) Director of Arts from 1965 to 1969, and Director for Arts and Humanities from 1970 to 1972. A self-described "artistic gadfly," Lloyd had a prestigious and varied career as a pianist, composer, conductor, teacher, and author.
  Norman Lloyd was born on November 8, 1909 in Pottsville, Pennsylvania. He received B.S. and M.S. degrees in music education with a specialization in teaching music theory from New York University.
  Lloyd taught at the New York University School of Education and Sarah Lawrence College from 1936 to 1946. He served as Director of Education at the Juilliard School of Music from 1946 to 1949, and then continued on as faculty at the school. In 1963, Lloyd left Juilliard to serve as Dean of the Conservatory of Music at Oberlin College. The same year, his influential method for teaching music theory was recognized with a Doctorate of Music from the Philadelphia Conservatory of Music. His acclaimed curriculum, "Literature and Materials of Music," was celebrated for its engaging, discussion-based approach that brought composers into the classroom to meet with students.
  The Cold War climate of the 1950s and 1960s prompted the Rockefeller Foundation to devote increasing resources to supporting and promoting American cultural programs. In September 1964 the RF established a new Arts Division separate from the Humanities, and Norman Lloyd was appointed to serve as the Division's Director in 1965. Lloyd was primarily responsible for cultural development in the United States; under his direction the Division supported playwrights, composers (including a separate grant for African American composers), symphony orchestras, music conservatories, and college theaters. When the RF merged the two programs again in 1970, Lloyd became Director for Arts and Humanities. He held this position until his retirement in December 1972.
  In addition to teaching and working for the RF, Lloyd composed and conducted dance scores and music for more than thirty documentary and experimental films. He also wrote articles about music and music education for publications including the Juilliard Review, Dance Observer, and Film Music, and authored and edited a number of works including The Fireside Book of Favorite American Songs, The Fireside book of Folk Songs, The Golden Encyclopedia of Music, and Fundamentals of Sight Singing and Ear Training (co-authored with Arnold Fish).
  Norman Lloyd died of leukemia in 1980 at the age of 70.
  - 1964- 1965 July (Box 265)
  - 1965 August-December (Box 266)
  - 1966 January-June (Box 266)
  - 1966 July-December (Box 266)
  - 1967 January-June (Box 267)
  - 1967 July-December (Box 267)
  - 1968 January-May (Box 267)
  - 1968 June-December (Box 268)
  - 1969 January-June (Box 268)
  - 1969 July-December (Box 268)
  - 1970 January-June (Box 269)
  - 1970 July-December (Box 269)
  - 1971 January-June (Box 269)
  - 1971 July-December (Box 270)
  - 1972 (Box 270)
  - Index, 1964-1972 (Box 270)
- Logan, John A., 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  Sardinia (Italy)
  - 1946-1947 (Box 271)
  - 1948-1951 (Box 271)
  - 1952-1954 (Box 271)
- Loomis, William Farnsworth, 0.39 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box and 1 microfilm box (35mm)
  - Index, 1949; Loomis, W. Farnsworth (William Farnsworth) (1914-1973); Rockefeller Foundation; 7 pages (Box 272, Reel M Loo 1, Frame 18)
    Index of diary for 1949; 7 pages. Includes "Visits 1949," which records the following itinerary of Loomis in 1949: Blacksburg, Virginia (V. P. I.- 8 Dec), Charlottesville (Univ. of Virginia- 9 Dec ), Denver (Univ. of Colorado- 28 Nov), Washington, D. C. (Howard- 6 Nov), Seattle (University of Washington- 1 Dec).
  - 1949, Loomis, W. Farnsworth (William Farnsworth) (1914-1973); Rockefeller Foundation; 28 pages (Box 272, Reel M Loo 1, Frame 25)
    This diary is a records of Dr. Loomis's inspections of university biochemistry laboratories and their research personnel between October 19 and December 28, 1949. Among the facilities visited in this particular diary are New York University, University of Virginia, V.P.I., University of Washington, Howard University, and University of Colorado. Dr. Loomis personal impressions of grant applicants and his recommendations concerning the laboratories and their research are provided.
    United States; Medical education; Biochemistry; Diaries
  - Index, 1950; Loomis, W. Farnsworth (William Farnsworth) (1914-1973); Rockefeller Foundation; 24 pages (Box 272, Reel M Loo 1, Frame 62)
    Index of diary for 1950; 24 pages. Includes "Visits 1949," which records the dates of Loomis's visits to 33 university research institutions in the United States.
  - 1950, Rockefeller Foundation; Loomis, W. Farnsworth (William Farnsworth) (1914-1973); 291 pages (Box 272, Reel M Loo 1, Frame 86)
    This diary is a record of Dr. Loomis's inspections of university biochemistry laboratories and their research personnel between January 10 and December 29, 1950. Over the course of the diary, Loomis visits 33 university laboratories across the country and interviews key researchers and Ph.D. candidates seeking RF support for their research. Dr. Loomis's personal impressions of grant applicants and his recommendations concerning the laboratories and their research are provided. Among the facilities visited is Oak Ridge, and the diary includes an archival photocopy of a New York Times article (Oct. 1, 1950), on Waldo Cohn, a researcher at Oak Ridge.
    Biochemistry; Diaries; United States; Medical education
  - Index, 1951; Loomis, W. Farnsworth (William Farnsworth) (1914-1973); Rockefeller Foundation; 23 pages (Box 272, Reel M Loo 1, Frame 409)
    Index of diary for 1951; 23 pages. Includes "Visits 1951," which records the dates of Loomis's visits to 24 research institutions in the United States and an extended trip to England, Sweden, and Denmark
    Sweden; United States; Medical education; indexes (reference sources); England; Denmark; Biochemistry
  - 1951, Rockefeller Foundation; Loomis, W. Farnsworth (William Farnsworth) (1914-1973); 276 pages (Box 272, Reel M Loo 1, Frame 432)
    This diary is a records of Dr. Loomis's inspections of university biochemistry laboratories and their research personnel between January 9 and December 21, 1951. Over the course of the diary, Loomis visits 24 university laboratories across the country and interviews key researchers and Ph.D. candidates seeking RF support for their research. Dr. Loomis personal impressions of grant applicants and his recommendations concerning the laboratories and their research are provided. From April 17 to May 10, Loomis visited university laboratories in England, Sweden, and Denmark for the same purposes, and his impressions of these facilities, his interviews with their personnel, and his recommendations for further RF interaction with these laboratories are recorded.
    Medical education; Sweden; England; Biochemistry; Denmark; Diaries; United States
- Lumsden, W. H. R., 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  - 1947-1949 (Box 273)
- Lyster, T. C., 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  - 1916, 1919-1921 (Box 273)